####################################### Gateway Details ####################################################################
 

Azure VPN Gateway Name              :gateway1
Azure VPN Gateway Resource Group    :dr
Azure VPN Gateway Location          :eastus

Configuration for Azure VPN Gateway:- 

VPN Type            :RouteBased
Is Active Active    :True
Is BGP enabled      :True

BGP Settings of Azure VPN Gateway:-

BGP Peer IP Address :10.0.1.20,10.0.1.21
BGP ASN             :65515

Please make sure the same is updated on the onpremise device if BGP is enabled for the connection. 
Refer: https://docs.microsoft.com/bs-latn-ba/azure/vpn-gateway/vpn-gateway-bgp-overview 


Gateway is Active-Active. Public IP's of Azure VPN Gateway are 40.71.44.165 and 13.90.57.188. Please make sure both the IP's are updated on your onpremise VPN devices.


####################################### Vnet/Subnet Details ################################################################



Azure VPN Gateway gateway1 is deployed in Vnet: Vnet1VPN under Subnet: GatewaySubnet
Address Range of Vnet Vnet1VPN : 10.0.1.0/24 10.0.25.0/28. 
Make sure the same is updated as Adress range on onpremise VPN device. 


Peering with Gateway VNet            :True 
Number of Peerings                   :2 



Peering Name                         :Gatewaypeering
Peered Vnet Name                     :DRvnet276
Address range                        :10.1.2.0/24
Virtual network acccess              :False
Gateway Transit enabled              :True

Please make sure the peered Vnet DRvnet276 address range 10.1.2.0/24 does not overlap with you onpremise network range. 
To connect to the peered network from onpremise, please make sure the range 10.1.2.0/24 is updated on your onpremise VPN device. Kindly confirm that the virtual network access to DRvnet276 and Gateway transit is enabled for the peering.


Peering Name                         :testpeer
Peered Vnet Name                     :Test-vnet
Address range                        :10.0.0.0/24
Virtual network acccess              :True
Gateway Transit enabled              :False

Please make sure the peered Vnet Test-vnet address range 10.0.0.0/24 does not overlap with you onpremise network range. 
To connect to the peered network from onpremise, please make sure the range 10.0.0.0/24 is updated on your onpremise VPN device. Kindly confirm that the virtual network access to Test-vnet and Gateway transit is enabled for the peering.


NSG/Route Table on Vnet Vnet1VPN :

No NSG and route table found associated with the Azure VPN Gateway Subnet. This aligns with Microsft recommendations. 
Please refer: https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/vpn-gateway/vpn-gateway-about-vpn-gateway-settings#gwsub


####################################### Connections/LocalNetwork Gateway #####################################################
 

 
Number of Connections associated with the gateway1 Azure VPN Gateway: 3


Connection no.: 1

Connection Name                      :Conn1 
Connection Status                    :Connected   
Last Connection Established time(UTC):04/28/2020 06:06:00 
Pre-shared Key                       :sprttech 
Local Network Gateway                :LNGVPN1 
Local Network Gateway IP             :104.211.208.97 
Local Network Gateway Address Range  :10.0.2.0/24 10.0.3.0/24
BGP configuration                    :False

As per Azure Gateway the onpremise gateway device IP is 104.211.208.97 and the onpremise network range is 10.0.2.0/24 10.0.3.0/24 
The Shared key used for the connection is:- sprttech. Please confirm the same on your onprem device.

Status is Connected for this connection. If you are still facing any connectivity issues that means your main mode for the tunnel is up but quick mode is failing. Please check for IPSEC/IKE policies configured on the onpremise device.
Refer: https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/vpn-gateway/vpn-gateway-about-vpn-devices 



Connection no.: 2

Connection Name                      :connSagar 
Connection Status                    :Connected   
Last Connection Established time(UTC):04/28/2020 06:06:00 
Pre-shared Key                       :serwtech
Local Network Gateway                :SagarLocal 
Local Network Gateway IP             :52.172.34.107 
Local Network Gateway Address Range  :10.2.0.0/16
BGP configuration                    :True

As per Azure Gateway the onpremise gateway device IP is 52.172.34.107 and the onpremise network range is 10.2.0.0/16 
The Shared key used for the connection is:- serwtech. Please confirm the same on your onprem device.

Status is Connected for this connection. If you are still facing any connectivity issues that means your main mode for the tunnel is up but quick mode is failing. Please check for IPSEC/IKE policies configured on the onpremise device.
Refer: https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/vpn-gateway/vpn-gateway-about-vpn-devices 



Connection no.: 3

Connection Name                      :test 
Connection Status                    :Unknown   
Pre-shared Key                       :hirthighi 
Local Network Gateway                :localNet2 
Local Network Gateway IP             :167.220.238.133 
Local Network Gateway Address Range  :10.0.0.0/28
BGP configuration                    :False

As per Azure Gateway the onpremise gateway device IP is 167.220.238.133 and the onpremise network range is 10.0.0.0/28 
The Shared key used for the connection is:- hirthighi. Please confirm the same on your onprem device.

Status is not connected for this connection. Please check the following: 
Azure Gateway Public IP and Vnet Address range is updated on the onpremise VPN device.
Onpremise VPN device's Public IP and network Address range is updated on Azure Local Network Gateway.
Please check that the right Pre-shared key is updated on both Azure and onpremise gateway. 
Validate the IPSEC/IKE policies configured on the onpremise device: https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/vpn-gateway/vpn-gateway-about-vpn-devices 

 

################################################################################################################################################# 

